--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/==--
协调：兜兜
翻译：故故 TRen 少亭 淡定哥 OROCHIzc 灰瑞狼
校对：fei非飞 爱帅蜀黍的影子
Who are you?
你是?
What is this?
那是什么?
- Your Majesty, caught him up in a fishing net.  - A fishing net.
- 陛下 我们在一张渔网里发现了他  - 渔网?
Sire, he's been telling stories. Stories that...
陛下 他一直在说故事 关于...
We believe he's found a...
我们觉得他发现了...
Ponce de Leon...
嗯 Ponce de Leon...
Says he found Ponce de Leon's ship.
他说他发现了Ponce de Leon的船
- Or sailed on it.  - No, I told you,
- 或是上过他的船  - 不可能 我不是早跟你说过
Ponce de Leon died 200 years ago.
Ponce de Leon200年前就死了嘛
Aye, but he died searching for something, didn't he?
是啊 但是他死的时候不是正在找什么东西吗?
The Fountain of Youth.
永生之泉
How soon can you sail?
你的船能行得多快?
With the tide.
得看潮有多大
加勒比海盗之惊涛怪浪
Over here! Lucky heather!
瞧一瞧看一看! 卖幸运草啦!
Pirate swords! Pirate swords!
卖海盗剑了! 海盗剑啊!
Pirate's execution today. Watch him swing!
今天有海盗要被处决 当街绞刑!
Pirate puppets!
卖海盗傀儡娃娃了!
Take that, you!
接招吧
Hurry, Papa, or we'll miss the hanging!
爸爸快点 不然要错过绞首了
It's not a hanging, dear, it's a trial. The hanging comes this afternoon.
不是绞刑 是审判 今天下午才是绞刑
Pirate hanging today!
今天有海盗要被处决!
Come on. Up you get.
起来 快
Move along, pirate.
快走 小海盗
Or should I say, "Captain Pirate" ?
或者应该叫你"海盗船长先生" ?
Come on. Come on! Up you go.
快点! 快走!
Quiet! Order!
肃静! 秩序!
Quiet!
肃静!
Now appearing before the court,
现在出现在大家面前的是
the notorious and infamous pirate, pillager,
声名狼藉无恶不作的海盗 抢劫犯
- and highwayman...  - Quiet!
- 而且是个路霸...  - 肃静!
Captain Jack Sparrow!
Jack Sparrow船长!
I told you, the name's Gibbs! Joshamee Gibbs!
我跟你说过多少次了 我名字叫Gibbs! Joshamee Gibbs!
- How many times...  - Hear ye, hear ye!
- 到底要说多少次...  - 听好了!
Presiding over these trials,
全体起立
all rise and attend, the Right Honorable Justice Smith!
主持此次审判的是 正义与公正的化身Smith先生
My dear sir.
不成敬意
Quiet!
肃静!
Now...
我们来看看...
what do we have here?
这位是?
Jack?
你是Jack?
Shut up!
闭嘴!
I don't recognize him.
我不认得他
Not necessary. You were saying?
没关系 你刚说什么来着?
Jack Sparrow is not my name.
我不是Jack Sparrow
My name is Joshamee Gibbs.
我叫Joshamee Gibbs
Is that so?
是吗?
- It says Jack Sparrow here.  - I told'em.
- 不是说Jack Sparrow在这儿嘛  - 我早说过了
I'm not Jack Sparrow, who I would be happy to identify to the court
我根本不是Jack Sparrow 如果能给我减刑的话我很乐意向法庭说出
- if it would help my case.  - I think that would be a poor defense,
- Jack Sparrow在哪  - 我觉得这是拙劣的狡辩
unless you want to be bludgeoned again like a harp seal.
除非你想再像格陵兰海豹(非法捕猎者通过棒击头部来捕捉海豹)那样被槌一次
The prisoner claims of being innocent
嫌犯说他被冤枉成
to being Jack Sparrow. How do you find?
Jack Sparrow了 你有什么看法?
No trial? But aren't we here to examine the evidence...
不讯问吗? 我们不正是来验证他是不是...
Foreman, your finding. Guilty?
陪审团主席先生 你觉得呢 有罪吗?
Guilty verdict means he'll hang.
裁定有罪的话他就要被处以绞刑
Hang him! String him up!
绞了他! 挂起来!
- Guilty?  - That's not fair!
- 那就有罪?  - 我冤枉啊!
Shut it.
安静
Joshamee Gibbs, the crime of which you've been found guilty of
Joshamee Gibbs先生 之前以为你是Jack Sparrow
is being innocent of being Jack Sparrow.
而有罪的决议无效
I hereby commute your sentence,
我在此宣判
and order that you be imprisoned for the remainder
你那悲惨的 垂死的 满脸络腮胡子的下半生
of your miserable, moribund, mutton-chopped life.
都将在监狱里度过
- What?!  - Hang him!
- 什么?!  - 绞死他!
- Hang him!  - There.
- 绞死他!  - 闭庭
- Balderdash!  - String him up! Hang him high!
- 别扯了!  - 绞死他 挂得高高的!
Means shall be arranged to transport this prisoner
我们得安排人手把这嫌犯
to the Tower of London.
押送到伦敦塔(古英国著名监狱)去
Thanks very much.
有劳了
Ta.
呼
Come on. Get up there.
过来 上车
Get up!
上去!
Hell's teeth. Now we're both headed for prison.
我的天呐 现在我们要一起去坐牢了
Not to worry. I've paid off the driver.
不用担心 我买通了驾车的
Ten minutes, we'll be outside London Town, horses waiting.
十分钟之后等我们出了伦敦 那边有马等着
Tonight, we make the coast.
今晚就能到海边
Then it's just a matter of finding a ship.
剩下的就是找一艘船了
- All part of the plan?  - Yes. Exactly.
- 这就是全部计划?  - 是的
I arrived in London Town just this morning
我今天早上来伦敦
to rescue one Joshamee Gibbs from one appointment with the gallows.
就为了从绞刑架上救下来一个Joshamee Gibbs
Seeing as how you're still alive,
鉴于你还活着
I'd say it's all been very successful thus far.
我不得不说 到目前为止 计划很成功
What happened to you, Gibbs?
你到底是怎么被抓到的 Gibbs?
I thought you were employed elsewhere or otherwise engaged.
我以为你被雇到了别的地方或是另有安排
Aye. But I always listened like a thief for news of the "Black Pearl" .
是啊 但是我常像贼一样打听"黑珍珠"号的传闻
Nobody's seen where she might next make port.
但没有人知道她下一站将驶向哪儿
Then, I hear a rumor:
然后我就听到了一个传言:
Jack Sparrow's in London with a ship and looking for a crew.
Jack Sparrow带着一艘船来了伦敦 正在寻找船员
- Am not.  - But that's what I heard.
- 我没有啊  - 但我听说的就是这样啊
Fact is, you're signing up men tonight.
传说中 你今天晚上要招人了
Pub called "The Captain's Daughter" .
在一个叫"船长女儿"的酒吧里
- Am not!  - Well, I thought it a bit odd,
-扯淡!  - 是啊 确实有点奇怪
but then, you've never been the most predictable of sorts.
但是 你又什么时候正经过呢
Tell me something.
你告诉我
There is another Jack Sparrow out there sullying my good name?
是不是有另一个Jack Sparrow在败坏我的名声?
- An impostor.  - Indeed.
- 冒充者  - 对
But... an impostor with a ship.
但是... 一个有艘船
And in need of a crew.
且正缺船员的冒充者
Which, as fate would have it, so am I.
命中注定他会找到船员的 就像我一样
What about you, Jack?
你最近怎么样 Jack?
Last I heard, you were hell-bent to find the Fountain of Youth.
上次听到的关于你的传闻 是说你在拼命的寻找永生之泉
Any luck?
找到了吗?
Circumstances arose and forced a compelling insight
情况有所改变 要求有敏锐的洞察力
regarding discretion and valor.
谨慎的判断以及勇气
- Meaning, you gave up.  - I did not.
- 就是说你放弃了  - 没有
I am just as bent as ever. Hellishly so.
我只是一如既往的坚强 极其坚强
I shall taste those waters, Master Gibbs. Mark my words.
Gibbs大师 听好了 总有一天我会尝到永生泉的水
Short trip.
这么快就到了
All part of the plan, yes?
这就是你的计划 全部计划?
No.
不是
You are Jack Sparrow?
你就是Jack Sparrow?
There should be a "Captain" in there somewhere.
你忘了加上"船长"的称谓
I've heard of you.
我听说过你
And you know who I am.
想必你也知道我是谁
Face is familiar. Have I threatened you before?
看上去挺面熟的 我以前绑架过你吗?
You are in the presence of George Augustus, Duke of Brunswick-Luneburg,
你面前的是Brunswick-Luneburg和Archtreasurer的公爵
Archtreasurer and Prince-elector of the Holy Roman Empire,
神圣罗马帝国王子选帝侯 大不列颠及爱尔兰的国王 当然也是你的国王
King of Great Britain and Ireland, and of you.
乔治 奥古斯都(就是著名的乔治二世)陛下
- Doesn't ring a bell.  - I am informed
- 还是没想起来  - 我听说
you have come to London to procure a crew for your ship.
你到伦敦是为了招募船员
Vicious rumor. Not true.
谣言可畏啊 根本没有的事
Then you lied to me when you told me you were Jack Sparrow.
那你就是跟我说谎 你根本不是Jack Sparrow
I am Jack Sparrow, but I'm not here to procure a crew.
我就是Jack Sparrow 但我不是来船员的
That is... someone else.
肯定是... 另有其人
Someone else named Jack Sparrow.
另一个Jack Sparrow?
You've brought me the wrong wastrel.
你们抓错人了
Find the proper one and dispose of this impostor.
赶快去给我找来真的Jack Sparrow 把这个冒牌货处理掉
No, wait, wait, wait. Hang on a minute.
不是 不是 等等
I'm Jack Sparrow, the one and only.
我就是独一无二的Jack Sparrow
And I am in London.
而且我正在伦敦
To procure a crew.
招募你的船员
To undertake a voyage,
准备着一次远航
- to the Fountain...  - What?
- 目标是永生...  - 什么?
Will someone please remove these infernal chains?
这些锁链吵死了 谁去给他拿掉?
Come, come.
正好 快来
We know you're in possession of a map.
我们知道你有一张地图
So confiscate the map, and to the gallows with him!
那就把地图没收了 把他绞了
Have you a map?
你真有张地图?
- No.  - Where is it?
- 没了  - 去哪儿了?
The truth? I lost it.
想听真话吗? 我弄丢了
- Quite recently, in fact.  - I have a report.
- 事实上 刚刚丢的  - 我的最新情报显示
The Spanish have located the Fountain of Youth.
西班牙人已经找到了永生之泉的位置
I will not have some melancholy Spanish monarch,
我决对不能让那位优柔寡断 而且还是个天主教徒的
a Catholic, gain eternal life!
西班牙国王 获得永生!
You do know the way to the Fountain?
你真的知道去往永生之泉的路?
Of course I do. Look at me.
那当然 看着我
You could guide an expedition.
那这样你带一个远征队去吧
With your permission, your heinie,
既然阁下你这么说
you will be providing, then, a ship...
那你得提供 一艘船...
and a crew.
还有全体船员
And a captain.
还有一位船长
Afternoon, sire.
午安 陛下
If I may be so bold, why is that man not in chains?
我斗胆问一句 这位先生怎么没被绑起来?
He must be manacled at once.
他必须拷起来才老实
At the center of my palace? Hardly.
在我宫殿的中心? 不需要
Hector.
嗨 赫克托耳(古希腊神话中的特洛城的大王子 这里是调侃的称谓)
How nice to see a fellow pirate make good of himself.
看见一个海盗同行过得这么好 我真高兴
Pirate? Nay. Privateer.
海盗? 不 我是个私掠船船长(女王颁发了执照的海盗)
On a sanctioned mission under the authority and protection of the Crown.
一个有王室保护 当局批准营业的私掠船长
As may be, but first,
也许吧 但是
what has become of my beloved Pearl?
你把我亲爱的珍珠号怎么了?
I lost the Pearl as I lost my leg.
我不仅失去了黑珍珠 连我的腿也是去了
- Lost the Pearl?  - Aye.
- 你居然搞丢了珍珠号?  - 是的
I defended her mightily enough, but she be sunk nonetheless.
我已经防护得够好了 但是她还是沉了
If that ship be sunk properly, you should be sunk with it.
既然你把黑珍珠搞沉了 那你也该一同陪葬进去
Captain Barbossa, each second we tarry, the Spanish outdistance us.
Barbossa船长 我们每耽搁一秒钟 西班牙人就把我们甩得更远
I have every confidence you will prevail and be rewarded
我相信你一定能胜利 到时候我就授予你
with the high station you so desire.
渴求已久的崇高的地位
- To serve doth suffice, sire.  - You, sir, have stooped.
- 一定让您满意 陛下  - 你 堕落了
Jack, our sands be all but run.
Jack 我们俩斗了半辈子了
Where's the harm in joining the winning side?
识时务者为俊杰 加入胜利的一边有什么不好?
And you do meet a nicer class of person.
而且你会结识一群更好的人
I understand everything.
除了你那一头假发
Except that wig.
我都能接受
He's getting away! Stop him!
他要逃走了! 拦住他!
- Head him off!  - No! Stop that pirate!
- 快阻止他!  - 快 阻止那个海盗
Come down!
快下来!
- He escaped?  - Leave it to me, sire.
- 就这么让他跑了?  - 交给我吧 陛下
Guards! Guards!
守卫! 守卫!
- Arms at ready!  - Aye, sir!
- 武装完毕?  - 是的 长官!
Find him!
给我搜!
Finders keepers!
谁捡到算谁的!
There!
在那儿!
Is that it?
这就完了?
Halt! Stop that carriage!
站住! 拦下那辆马车!
Head him off!
拦住他!
Out of the way!
别挡路!
Stop that pirate!
拦住那个海盗!
Move out of the way!
走开 别挡路!
Stop that man!
挡住他!
Don't let him get away!
别让他跑了!
Fire!
开火!
He's getting away! After him! Stop him!
他要逃走了 追上他 别让他跑了!
After him!
追上他!
Filthy pirate.
你个肮脏的海盗
Hello, Jackie.
嗨 Jackie
Hello, Dad.
嗨 老爸
I heard you're putting together a crew.
我听说你在招募船员
If enough people keep saying it, it must be true.
三人成虎事多有
I heard where you're headed. The Fountain.
我听说了 你要去永生泉
Have you been there?
你去过吗?
Does this face look like it's been to the Fountain of Youth?
就我这张老脸 像是去过永生之泉的人吗?
- Depends on the light.  - Son, the Fountain.
- 这得看光线亮不亮  - 儿子啊 去永生泉
There'll be items required for the profane ritual.
得找到渎神仪式的献祭品
Two chalices.
就是那两个圣杯
- On the map there was a chalice.  - Two, silver.
- 地图上确实有一个圣杯  - 不 是两个 而且是银的
From the Ponce de Leon's ship. You'll need both.
在Ponce de Leon的船上 两个你都需要
- For?  - The ritual. Don't be a fool, Jackie.
- 干嘛用?  - 献祭仪式啊 千万别犯傻 小杰
Find out every detail before you set sail.
出发前一定要搞清每一个细节
Oh, set sail. Love to.
哦 航行 我喜欢
But for that, I may need a ship.
但是我得先有条船
Those folk, over there, they have a ship.
那边的那些人 他们有条船
They're signing up sailors right now.
他们现在正在征集水手
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特射中了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 所以我放弃了所有闪闪发光的金 #
And one last thing, Jackie.
最后我再补充一点 Jackie
The Fountain will test you. Mark my words.
记住我的话 永生泉是个考验
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特射中了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 所以我放弃了所有闪闪发光的金 #
# There is nothing can console me #
# 没有什么能慰藉我 #
# But my jolly sailor bold #
# 除了我愉快勇敢的水手们 #
I hear you be recruiting a crew.
我听说你正在招募水手
Aye. That is,
对 是的
Jack Sparrow be putting together a modest venture.
Jack Sparrow要起航去探险
You got some nerve, ain't ya?
你倒是挺大胆的 啊?
Turning up here dressed like that?
穿成这样 跑到这里来?
What are you, some kind of impostor?
你是谁 你这个次品假货?
Have you any idea who I am, mate?
伙计 你看不出来我是谁?
Oi, muckers!
嘿 朋友们!
There's a bloke here what's forgotten his own name!
这个家伙竟然忘记了自己叫什么!
Lads, I'm sailing with Sparrow.
伙计们 我要跟着Sparrow出海
Who'll buy a sailor a drink?
谁能请我这个水手一杯酒?
Who's next?
下一个是谁?
Bring us some more of those ones.
给我们再来点儿
Yeah, make it four.
对 来四个
You've stolen me, and I'm here to take meself back.
你盗用了我的名号 今天我就要把它夺回来
Stop doing that.
别学我
Only one person alive knows that move.
世上只有一人知道这招
Always wanted to do that.
我一直想吻你
Hello, Angelica.
Angelica 你好啊
Hello, Jack. Are you impressed?
你好 Jack 不错吧?
I think I almost killed you once or twice there.
我想有一两回合 我差点就把你杀了
I'm touched at this most sincerest form of flattery.
这种最诚挚的恭维 可让我无比感动
But why?
但为什么要这么做?
You were the only pirate I thought I would pass for.
所有海盗里 我只想去冒充你
That is not a compliment.
这可不是在赞扬我
Don't worry, Jack. I forgave you a long time ago.
Jack 别担心 我很早就原谅你了
- For what? For leaving you?  - Recall that I left you.
- 原谅我什么? 当初离你而去吗?  - 好好想想 是我自己离开你的
A gentleman allows a lady to maintain her fictions.
所有绅士 不都会留给小姐们一丝幻想
Look, Sparrow. As long as my sailors get their money,
仔细听着 Sparrow 我的水手只要能拿到钱
they're willing to put up with any number of peculiarities.
任何事情他们都会不闻不问
There is one peculiarity with which I will not put up with.
有一件事情我倒是忍受不了
I will be impersonated as "Captain." Nothing less.
你冒充我 漏了"船长"两个字 就这件事
Well, for that, you need a ship,
哼 要做船长 你得有艘船才行
and as it turns out, I have one.
而我 恰好就有一艘
I could use a ship.
我正好需要一艘
I hear tell you've been to the Fountain.
我听说你已经到过永生之泉了
There be a lot of hear-telling going on these days.
哎 真是谣言满天飞
- The Fountain of Youth.  - Dearest Angelica, fret not.
- 我说的是不老泉  - 我最亲爱的Angelica 不要烦躁
You still have a few usable years left.
你有生之年还长着呢
Always so charming.
你永远都那么有魅力
You didn't answer me.
但你没有回答我的问题
Aye. Regarding the Fountain. Waste of time, really...
嗯 说到这永生之泉 简直就是浪费时间 真的
Milady, I see unseamanlike fellows of an officious-looking nature.
夫人 有些不像是水手的人进来了 好像是当官的
Wretched pirates! Find 'em! Maggots!
可恶的海盗! 找到他们! 这些败类!
Friends of yours?
是你的朋友?
I may have unintentionally slighted some king or other.
我好像不小心得罪了国王什么的
Open it!
打开!
- Yeah, you haven't changed.  - Implying the need?
- 是啊 你真是死性不改  - 那要改成活性?
Yes.
对啊
Open this door, in the name of His Majesty.
我以国王陛下的名义命令你 打开这扇门
You betrayed me. You seduced me and you used me.
你背叛了我 你引诱 利用了我
I was innocent of the ways of men.
我根本不了解你们男人的把戏
You demonstrated a lot of technique for someone I supposedly corrupted.
对付我这样个老手 你的伎俩不可谓不多啊
Imminent danger. Here, now, milady!
灾难当头啦 夫人 现在赶快到这儿来!
Open it!
开门!
I was ready to take my vows. And you...
我正准备宣誓 而你...
What were you doing in a Spanish convent, anyway?
你在那家西班牙修女院到底做了什么?
Mistook it for a brothel. Honest mistake.
我还以为是妓院呢 我不是故意的
- There he is!  - Over there!
- 他在那儿!  - 在那里!
We are at a disadvantage.
我们场面不占优啊
Speak for yourself. Unlike some who pretend to be,
那是你 我才不像某人 要假装别人
but cannot, in fact, hold a candle to,
却又技不如人
I am Captain Jack Sparrow.
我才是Jack Sparrow船长
How can you say I used you?
你怎么能说我是在利用你呢?
You know exactly how.
你自己心里清楚
I know, but how can you say it?
我是知道 但是你怎么能这么说呢?
- So, what is it?  - What is what?
- 好啊 那到底是怎么回事?  - 什么怎么回事?
About the Fountain.
我说不老泉
What do you know?
你到底知道些什么?
You don't happen to be in possession
你不会碰巧就有
of two silver chalices, circa Ponce de León?
Ponce de León的两个银杯吧?
- No.  - Thought not.
- 我没有  - 想想也是
- Why?  - I hear stories.
- 为什么这么说?  - 我听到些故事
Rumors.
一些谣言
You are, of course, aware of the ritual.
当然你也知道仪式的事情
Yes, I am.
对 我是知道
What is it? What is required?
仪式到底是怎样? 需要什么?
A mermaid, Jack.
Jack 需要一条美人鱼
There's been a mistake.
有一个误会
It's a life sentence, not death. Life!
是终身监禁 不是死刑! 是终身监禁!
- Barbossa.  - Thank you, gentlemen.
- Barobssa是你  - 先生们 谢谢
I trust you can tie a noose.
系个绞绳应该没问题吧
That's a hard thing,
让一个人系好自己的绞绳
forcing a man to twist his own hanging rope.
这可是件难事
You must lie in your bed the way you made it.
你这是自作自受
What's happened to you?
你到底怎么了?
- Where be Jack Sparrow?  - He escaped.
- Jack Sparrow在哪里?  - 他逃走了
I'm on a tight schedule, Gibbs.
Gibbs 我时间可不多啊
The HMS Providence sets sail at first light.
卓识号帆船天亮之时就要出发
If you do not care to watch it hanging here dead,
如果你不想尸体在这儿被吊着
with a mouth full of flies...
满嘴都是苍蝇...
speak now.
那就坦白吧
Take me with you. Any point of the compass...
把我带上吧 地图上的每一处...
Take you where, Gibbs? The Fountain? Aye?
带你去哪儿啊 Gibbs? 去不老泉? 是吧?
Is that where Jack be headed?
Jack也要去那儿吗?
Have you anything you can offer me, Gibbs?
Gibbs 你到底能给我什么呢?
Anything at all?
什么都没有?
Upon me naked word, you'll not see the dawn.
我言出必行 你将再也见不到日出
Hand it over.
拿过来
- You fool!  - I had just enough time
- 你这个蠢蛋!  - 我刚好有时间
to study those infernal circles.
把这些该死的航线研究了一番
Every route, every destination. All safe... in here.
每条线路 每个地点 都在这儿存着呢
Welcome back to His Majesty's navy, Master Gibbs.
Gibbs先生 欢迎回到皇家海军
Show a leg, sailor!
起床 水手!
Aye, sir.
是 长官
What?
什么?
- There's been a horrible mistake.  - Keep moving.
- 这儿有个天大的误会  - 继续走
- I'm not supposed to be here.  - Many a man's woken up at sea,
- 我不应在这儿的  - 许多人在船上醒来
no idea what, when, wherefore or why.
不知何事 何时 何故
No memory of the night afore, whence he signed up
不记得前晚他应征的时候
and drank away all his bonus money.
喝的酒耗光了他所有的雇佣金
No, no, no. You don't understand, mate.
不不不 伙计 你不明白
I'm Captain Jack Sparrow. The original. The only.
我是Jack Sparrow船长 真正的Jack Sparrow 唯一的Jack Sparrow
Scrum, and the pleasure's all mine. Now, keep moving.
我是Scrum 幸会了 好了 继续往前走
Scrum.
嘿 Scrum
Get your elbows in!
靠过来!
Why is there a glass coffin?
那个玻璃棺材是干什么的?
Do I look like a man in charge?
我像是个掌事的么?
- Where am I?  - 'Scuse me, Captain Sparrow, sir.
- 我到底在哪里?  - 抱歉 Sparrow船长
I be right honored to welcome you aboard
我很荣幸欢迎你来到
our world-renowned vessel of infamy, Queen Anne's Revenge.
我们恶名昭著的玛丽皇后复仇号
Blackbeard.
黑胡子
Work!
干活!
- He's a curious one.  - He's been zombiefied.
- 他倒挺有意思的  - 他就像个僵尸
Zombiefied.
我说 僵尸
Blackbeard's doing. All the officers are the same.
黑胡子把他们变成僵尸 船上长官谁都这样
Makes 'em more compliant.
让他们更加顺从
And perpetually ill-tempered.
而且还这么坏脾气
- Come on. Scrub.  - Yeah.
- 来吧 擦啊  - 好
Pull! Pull! Pull!
拉啊! 拉啊! 拉啊!
Five days underway, at least.
我们至少航行了五天了
Aye. You can tell that by the smell of the sea?
是啊 你是通过海水的气味闻出来的吗?
Smell of the crew.
是船员身上的气味
Oi. What did that poor sod do?
嘿 那个可怜的伙计干了什么?
And how can I make sure to knot?
我要怎么不重蹈他的覆辙?
Him? Churchly fellow.
他呀? 是教会的人
Always going on about the Lord Almighty.
总是念叨着全能的天主
Bible-thumper on this ship?
在船上推销圣经的?
A missionary is his story.
他是个传教士
What I heard was he got captured in a raid.
我听说他是一次掠夺中被俘的
Rest of the ship got killed, but not 'im.
其他船员都被杀了 除了他
First mate wouldn't let it happen
大副不让杀他
on account of his premier standing with the Lord.
出于他和上帝的联系
A first mate sticking her neck out for some prisoner.
她真是第一个 豁出性命帮囚犯的大副
That you don't see.
这可不常见
"Her" ? First mate is a "her"?
你说"她" ? 大副是个女的?
Back to work!
回去干活!
Steady as she goes.
稳速前航
You are a ruthless, soulless, cross-grained cur.
你这个无理 残酷 无情的混蛋
- I told you I had a ship.  - No, Blackbeard has a ship,
- 我告诉过你我有一艘船  - 不 是黑胡子的船
upon which I am now imprisoned.
还害我现在被困在这船上
We can do this, Jack.
Jack 我们能做到的
The Fountain of Youth, like you always wanted.
你不是你一直想得到不老泉吗?
Blackbeard. Edward Teach. The pirate all pirates fear.
黑胡子 全名Edward Teach 连海盗都惧怕的海盗
Resurrector of the dead in his spare time.
没事就让死人复生
- He will listen to me.  - He listens to no one.
- 他会听我的  - 他谁也不会听
Maybe to his own daughter?
也许会听自己亲女儿的?
Daughter as in... beget by?
女儿... 是亲生的?
Long-lost. Recently found.
我们失散多年了 最近才重逢
Who loves her dear papa with all her soul.
我深爱着我父亲
- He bought that?  - I sold that.
- 他信这鬼话了?  - 我让他信了
Then it's the Fountain of Youth for him,
那不老泉就是他的了
or him and you, not you and me.
或者是你们两个的 而不是你我的
No, Jack, that's the best part.
不是的 Jack 还有件好事儿
He will be dead.
他一定会死的
You'll be handling that part yourself, then?
那这事儿就你自己来操办 是吧?
There is a prophecy.
有一则预言
Maybe you don't believe in the supernatural.
也许你不相信超自然的东西
Oh, no, no. I've seen a thing or two.
哦 不不 超自然的东西我也见过一两回
The prophecy is this:
语言是这样的:
Blackbeard will meet his death within a fortnight
两周之内 黑胡子难逃一死
at the hands of a one-legged man.
他会被一个独腿的人所杀
That's why he needs the Fountain, Jack.
Jack 这就是为什么他需要不老泉
Master Gibbs, short we are a map.
Gibbs先生 我们没有航图
Perhaps you'd be so kind as to provide us an heading.
也许您能给我们指点航向
Be a gem and pour me a gulper.
给我点好处 来口酒啊
Nay. We be privateers, not pirates, Master Gibbs.
不 Gibbs先生 我们是私掠船水手 不是海盗
And in the king's name, we behave as such.
以国王之名 我们要有水手的行为准则
Aye, Captain.
是 船长
Be we on the proper course, Gibbs?
Gibbs 我们在正确的航线上吗?
Aye, it be proper. There's your proof.
是 航线是正确的 证据就在那儿
The Spaniard.
西班牙人
All hands! Battle stations! Get to windward!
所有船员! 进入战斗岗位! 到迎风面!
- All hands, windward!  - Harden up two points!
所有人到迎风面!  - 船帆勒紧两度!
- Two points!  - Cast loose the cannons!
- 两度!  - 火炮解缆!
- Gunners, take posts!  - Take position! Gunners ready, sir!
- 炮手各就各位!  - 各就各位! 长官 炮手已就位!
- Out! Thrust! - Await orders.
- 火炮解开! 装填! - 待命
Steady!
预备!
Guns armed, awaiting orders, sir.
长官 炮弹已上膛 待命
Sir. Orders, sir?
长官 下令啊 长官?
He never so much as turned his head.
他根本没把我们放在眼里
The Fountain is the prize.
不老泉才是终极的奖赏
It appears we be not even worth the time it'd take to sink us.
好像他们根本不愿花这个时间 来击沉我们
And now we've fallen behind. All hands, make more sail!
现在我们已经落后啦 全体船员 全速前进!
All hands, more sail!
所有人 全速前进!
Ride hard between wind and tide!
利用风力和海潮向前航行!
The topic, gentlemen, is mutiny.
先生们 我们要讨论的 是哗变
Mutiny most foul.
最彻底的起义
Aye. I signed up to sail under Jack Sparrow, not some pretender.
对 我应征跟着Jack Sparrow船长 而不是冒牌货
And a lady, at that.
而且这人还是个女的
And mention was failed to be made of this uncanny crew.
也没提到过船上还有僵尸
Make my toes curl, they do.
吓得我腿都软了
I got 'em. All of them.
我弄到了 都在这儿了
- Well done.  - Good lad.
- 干得漂亮  - 好伙计
On to it, then. Blackbeard.
回到正题 黑胡子
- What are his habits?  - Stays mostly to his cabin.
- 他有什么习惯?  - 总是呆在自己的船舱里
That's right, mostly to his cabin.
是啊 总是在自己的船舱里面
- Yes, but when he comes out...  - He don't really come out.
- 是 但是当他出来的时候...  - 他好像真的不出来
He must come out sometime.
他肯定什么时候会出来的
Not really, no.
真的不会 不会
Any of you sail with him before?
你们中可有人以前跟他出过海?
- No, no.  - I've never.
- 没有 没有  - 我从来没有
Definitely not.
肯定没有啦
- Any of you seen him before?  - Not really, no.
- 又没人之前见过他?  - 真的没有啊 没有
Stays to his cabin, no one sailed with him,
呆在船舱里 没人跟他出过海
no one's seen him...
没有人见过他
Good news, gentlemen. This is not Blackbeard's ship.
好消息啊 先生们 这不是黑胡子的船
This is not the Queen Anne's Revenge.
这不是玛丽女王复仇号
No, this be the Queen Anne's Revenge, right enough.
不 这就是玛丽女王复仇号
How do you know?
你怎么知道?
I've seen the name, on the back of the ship.
我在船尾看到了这个名字
Gentlemen, sirs, fellow conscriptees...
先生们 诸位 身陷囹圄的伙计们...
you have been monstrously deceived.
你们被蒙惨了
- We are decepted, then?  - Yes.
- 啥 我们被骗了?  - 对
You've nay been informed of a destination.
你们根本不知道此行的目的
Death lies before us
当我们向不老泉航行时
as we sail for the Fountain of Youth.
死亡也在步步逼近
It would be a sorry plight, mates.
情况不妙啊 伙计们
- Death, for certain.  - The garden of darkened souls.
- 必死无疑了  - 黑暗之灵的花园
- Untimely our ends will be.  - Unless...
- 宿命末途将至  - 除非...
we take the ship.
我们占了这艘船
We take the ship, then. Now!
我们这就占了它 就在此刻!
Go on, then.
行动起来吧
- Help me, shipmates!  - Give it to 'em!
- 帮把手啊 船员们!  - 家伙给他们!
- Wake up! It's ours!  - Come on!
- 醒醒吧! 船是我们的!  - 上啊!
Get up! Off your backside!
起来! 下去吧你!
- Get off your fannies!  - Take it to them, lads!
- 屁股挪开!  - 给他们剑 伙计们!
Help me! Fight!
帮把手! 战斗吧!
Jack.
Jack啊
If this is a dream, you can keep the sword and boots on.
如果这是梦 你可以留着你的剑和靴
- If it's not...  - It's a dream.
- 如果不是...  - 这是场梦
No, it's not!
不 不是!
I thought I should give you fair warning, we're taking the ship.
我想我该正式通知你 我们正在占领这艘船
Nothing personal.
我可不会徇私情啊
Think you might be better off if you just...
你消停点 或许就没那么麻烦了...
Stay out of it.
置身事外吧
Wretch!
无耻之徒!
You're either with us or against us!
要么加入 要么与我们为敌!
I am not with you, neither am I against you!
我不会加入 也不会与你们为敌!
Can he do that?
他这样可以吗?
He's religious. I believe it's required.
他是教徒 貌似这样是规定
Fight to the bitter end, you cack-handed deck apes!
奋战到底 你们这帮笨手笨脚的甲板怪物!
Take him, men. Tie him down tight!
拿下他 伙计们 绑紧了!
The ship is ours!
船是我们的了!
Gentlemen.
先生们
I be placed in a bewilderment.
我很困惑
There I were, resting,
刚刚我在那儿 歇息
and upon a sudden, I hear an ungodly row on deck.
顷刻间便听见甲板上 杀声喧天
Sailors abandon their posts
船员未经授命
without orders, without leave.
便擅离其位
Men before the mast,
船桅前的伙计
taking the ship for themselves.
宣称将这船占为己有
What be that, First Mate?
这是怎么回事 大副?
- Mutiny, Captain.  - Again?
- 是叛乱 船长  - 再说一遍?
- Mutiny!  - Aye.
- 是叛乱!  - 噢
Mutiny.
叛乱
And what fate befalls mutineers?
叛乱者是何下场?
Now, we know the answer to that, do we not?
该当何罪 你们可清楚?
Mutineers hang!
处以绞刑!
Captain, I wish to report a mutiny.
船长 我想报告一场叛乱
I can name fingers and point names.
我能将叛乱者一一指出
No need, Mr. Sparrow.
不必了 Sparrow先生
They are sheep. You, their shepherd.
他们是绵羊 你便是牧羊人
Have I mentioned, sir, what a lovely daughter you have?
我可否提及过 您有位可爱动人的女儿?
A fitting last sight for a doomed soul.
一个悲哀灵魂 死前最后看眼这美丽世界吧
Remember, Father. We need him.
记住 爸爸 我们需要他
If I don't kill a man every now and then,
我要不时不时开点杀戒
- they forget who I am.  - Coward!
- 他们该忘记我是谁了  - 懦夫!
They do not forget.
他们可没忘了
Your crew sees you for the miscreant you are.
你在众人眼中 罪恶滔天
A coward, no matter how many you slay.
尽管你肆意杀戮 却始终是个懦夫
Twice in one day, I find myself in a bewilderment.
一天当中这是第二次 我感到困惑了
You are not bewildered, you are afraid.
你并非困惑 而是畏惧
You dare not walk the path of righteousness, the way of the light.
你不敢踏入正义之路 光明之途
No, sir. The truth is it be much simpler than all that.
不 先生 事实要简单的多
- I am a bad man.  - That, too.
- 我是个坏人  - 这也没错
I might have to kill you too, catechist.
我也不得不杀了你 传道师
- No!  - All Latin blood like her mother.
- 不!  - 拉丁血统 真像她妈
Father, I beg you.
爸爸 求你了
There I be again, forgetting why the missionary is here.
又来了 我都忘记这传教士为啥会在这儿
My daughter fears for my soul, or what's left of it.
我女儿想拯救我的灵魂 还能有什么
You truly wish to save me, my child?
你真想救赎我 孩子?
Every soul can be saved.
每个灵魂都可以拯救
Be that true, young cleric?
当真 小牧师?
Yes. Though you I see as a bit of a long shot.
是的 尽管在我看来 你是机会渺茫
Still, I pray for every unfortunate soul on this hell-bound vessel.
可我仍然会为这地狱之船上的 每一个不幸灵魂祷告
You disarm me with your faith.
你们的信仰使我缴械认输
Eight bells!
八击钟!
Which of you unfortunate souls stood watch?
你们这些不幸的人儿 谁负责放哨的?
- I did. I stood watch.  - Gunner.
- 是我 我放哨的  - 炮手
You?
你?
Aye.
是的
嗯
The cook.
是厨子
Perfect. Lower the longboat!
好极了 放小艇!
Bring her about!
掉头!
- Why do you do this?  - Mutiny. Our laws be clear.
- 你为什么要这么做?  - 叛乱 我们的法纪很明晰
Our laws allow the Captain to show leniency.
我们的法纪更希望船长宽慈仁厚
I have given this man a chance to determine his fate,
我已经给此人机会 性命在他自己手中
a gift not afforded to all.
这一恩赐不是谁都能得到的的
Oh, you now.
哦 现在该你了
Chance to show the worth of your prayers.
给你个机会 展示你祷告的力量
Pray he be delivered from... evil?
祈祷他从... 罪恶中解脱?
Course made!
找准航向!
Stop. Give that man a chance. Give yourself a...
停下 给他一次机会 给你自己一次...
You know when I feel closest to our Maker?
知道我什么时候 会感到离造物主最近吗?
When I see suffering, pain and anguish.
当我看到苦难 悲恸 绝望时
That's when the true design of this world is revealed.
世间的真实面目在我眼前呈现
And I see it revealed when in times of hardship and tragedy,
当困难 悲剧降临 仁慈怜悯长存人心
kindness and compassion are shown to those in need.
这才是世间的真实面目
Perhaps you should pray for him to be unharmed, yes?
或许你该祈祷他安然无恙 是吧?
- Please, there's still hope...  - Again!
- 求你 还有希望...  - 再来!
I actually have no interest in the Fountain whatsoever,
其实我对什么不老泉 没啥兴趣
so, if your heart is set,
所以 要是你已经拿定主意
you may drop me off anywhere you like.
随你把我丢到哪儿
That'll be all, Quartermaster.
就这样 舵手
Your words surround you like fog and make you hard to see.
你的话语云山雾罩 让我看不透
And what of you, the mighty Blackbeard?
那你呢 只手遮天的黑胡子?
Beheaded they say. Still, your body swam
他们说你身首异处 你的身躯绕船游了三圈
three times around your ship, then climbed back onboard.
然后又爬上船来
And here you are, running scared.
现在你毫发未损 为何如此恐惧
- Scared.  - To the Fountain.
- 胆颤心惊  - 为了找寻不老泉
The Quartermaster sees things before they happen.
舵手能未卜先知
He has foreseen my death, and so the fates have spoken.
他预见我的死亡 命运早有定数
The threads of destiny woven.
在劫难逃啊
You have a ridiculously high regard for fate, mate.
你太高估命运的力量了 伙计
- And you?  - Me?
- 你呢?  - 我?
I'm skeptical of predicting any future... which includes me.
我对未卜先知的事深表怀疑... 包括我的命运
It'd be foolish to battle fate, but I'd be tempted to cheat it.
反抗命运是件傻事 但我愿意尝试
I will reach the Fountain. You will lead me.
我会找到不老泉 在你的指引下
That knife will serve you no better than the mutiny you devised.
那把刀和你谋划的叛变一样 对你毫无益处
Mutiny served me well.
叛变很有效果
It gained me an audience with you.
它让我见识你的真面目
Aye.
是啊
To warn you.
然后奉告一声
Regarding your first mate,
你的大副
who pretends to be persons she is not.
假扮他人 弄巧成拙
Do tell.
接着说
She is not your daughter.
她不是你的女儿
You dare to speak thusly of my flesh and blood?
你胆敢这么说我的亲生骨肉?
Sir, the woman is consummate in the art of deception.
先生 这女人骗计超群
I know. As I mostly unwittingly set her on her wicked path.
我知道 尽管是我无意使她走上骗子这条路
Though I cannot claim credit
我也不能说
for her existing abundance of natural talent.
她天赋秉然 源之于我
Angelica. My beloved daughter,
Angelica 我深爱的女儿
the one true good thing I have done in this life,
我一生的最佳杰作
and you claim to be the one who corrupted her?
你敢这样诋毁她?
Sir, what she is is pure evil.
先生 她的本源是邪恶
More to be feared than a wild beast.
比野兽更可怕
Hungry wild beast with gnashing teeth.
饥肠辘辘 咬牙切齿
Vengeful, hungry from hell beast...
复仇心切 来自地狱的野兽...
- Father?  - Sweetness!
- 爸爸?  - 小可爱!
No need to hurt him, Father.
不必伤害他 爸爸
He will help us. Won't you, Jack?
他会帮我们的 是吧 Jack?
You see? Even now, she attends to your welfare,
看到没? 直到现在 她还关心你的安危
giving lie to the claims you make of her.
即使你那样百般诋毁她
You will lead us to the Fountain. Yes?
你会带领我们去不老泉 是吗?
Put another way.
换句话说
If I do not make it to the Fountain in time...
如果我不能及时赶到不老泉...
neither will you.
你也别想
I'll have a wee look-see at those charts straight away then, shall I?
我马上看看这些航海图 好吧?
Sir.
先生
- Aye?  - Captain, sir,
- 怎么了?  - 船长
I am unhappy to report rumors, sir,
我很遗憾向您汇报
among the crew, as to our destination.
在船队中 疯传关于目的地的谣言
Shut your trap and make way.
闭上你的狗嘴 滚蛋
- That's the way of it, then.  - No disrespect, sir.
- 事实的确如此了  - 无意冒犯 先生
What do the men fear? Say it. Speak the words.
他们在怕什么? 说 快说啊
Whitecap Bay.
白帽湾
Aye, Whitecap Bay.
喔 白帽湾啊
And every worthless seaman fears the name, and rightly so,
每一个卑微的水手都怕这名字
though few know why or dare to ask.
尽管没人知道原因 也没人敢问
Be the stories true?
谣言是真的吗?
Say what robs you of your staunch heart, Gibbs,
说说看 是谁夺走了你坚定的心 Gibbs
or forever leave it to the wider fields of fancy.
要么你就做你的青天白日梦去吧
Mermaids, Captain.
人鱼 船长
Aye. Mermaids.
是喔 人鱼
Sea ghouls, devil fish, dreadful in hunger for flesh of man.
海上恶魔 嗜食人血
Mermaid waters, that be our path.
我们就是要取道人鱼的水域
Cling to your soul, Gibbs,
顾好你的灵魂 Gibbs
as mermaids be given to take the rest...
人鱼会把人吃到...
to the bone.
只剩骨头
Steady! Steady, men! Find your courage,
稳住! 稳住 伙计们! 拿出你们的勇气
or be ready to purpose your fear!
直面恐惧!
Save yourselves!
自我拯救吧!
- Man overboard!  - Nay! A deserter.
- 有人落水了!  - 不! 那是逃兵
- Come about.  - Nay!
- 抢风调向  - 不!
Gentlemen, I shall not ask any more of any man than what
先生 我不会强人所难 可我要问：
that man can deliver, but I do ask this: Are we not king's men?
我们是不是国王的臣民?
Aye.
是
- On the king's mission?  - Aye.
- 受国王之命?  - 是
I did not note any fear in the eyes of the Spanish as they passed us by.
西班牙人从身边掠过时 我没在他们眼中找到恐惧
- Are we not king's men?  - Aye!
- 我们难道不是国王的臣民?  - 我们是!
Aye! Hands all off, and bear away!
那好! 各就各位 转向!
Stave on ahead to Whitecap Bay!
直行驶向白帽湾!
Bear on, Whitecap Bay!
目标 白帽湾！
Come.
来啊
Little drink?
喝点?
Wine, music, candlelight.
葡萄酒 音乐 烛光
I think we've traveled down this road before, Jack.
这情景有印象吧 Jack
Yes, we have.
有印象
I remember it well.
我记得很清楚
Winding, twisting and turning, gyrating, writhing.
弯曲 扭曲 转身 摇摆 翻滚..
Incessant writhing.
翻来覆去
Do you recall Saint Dominique?
记得Saint Dominique吗?
La Martinique.
是La Martinique
I tried to kill you in Saint Dominique.
在Saint Dominique我试图杀了你
Either or.
没得逞
Hardly appropriate for a first mate.
大副喝酒 不大像话
Was I the first? I've often wondered.
我是你的第一次吗? 我总想知道
You can be so charming when you want something, Jack.
你有所企图的时候很迷人 Jack
The trick is finding out what.
关键是找出你想要的
The truth, then, is it?
真相 是吗?
Blackbeard has served his purpose.
黑胡子达到了他的目的
You and I can go to the Fountain together,
你我一同前往不老泉
where we shall bathe one another in equal shares of fame
沐浴其中 纵情欢乐
and other assorted debaucheries.
尽享欢愉
And I'll tell you the ritual of the Fountain.
而我会告诉你不老之泉的仪式
Yes. The profane ritual.
对 渎神的仪式
Can I trust you, Jack?
我能信任你吗 Jack?
- I need you on my side.  - Oh, my dearest Angelica.
- 我需要你站在我这边  - 哦 我最亲爱的Angelica
You and I are as thick as thieves, love.
亲爱的 我们是龙凤双盗啊啊
Tell me the rules.
告诉我规矩
Water from the Fountain of Youth.
不老泉的泉水
The shimmering tear of a mermaid.
人鱼闪耀的泪水
The silver chalices of Ponce de Le.
Ponce de Le的银色圣杯
With these items...
有了这些...
- Yes?  - With these items,
- 怎么?  - 有了这些
you may take all the years of life from another, Jack.
你就能从另一个那里获得永久的青春 Jack
You know what that means.
你知道什么意思
We cannot go alone, you and I.
我们俩不能单独去
The ritual requires a victim.
仪式需要一名牺牲者
- That is unfortunate.  - Yes, it is.
- 真不幸  - 是啊
I found my desire for the Fountain greatly lessened.
我发现自己寻找不老泉的欲望大大消减了
But there is something onboard you do want.
但是船上有你想要的东西
What about Blackbeard?
黑胡子呢?
He's in the chart room. We'll have to be quick.
他在海图室 我们得快点
He keeps each ship as a prize.
他把每艘船都当作战利品保存起来
You help me, and I promise you your pick.
只要你帮助我 无论你挑哪艘 我都能许诺给你
Though I think I know the one you will choose.
虽然我知道你会选哪艘
The Black Pearl in a bottle?
黑珍珠号在瓶子里?
Why is the Black Pearl in a bottle?
为什么黑珍珠号会在瓶子里?
He's even more annoying in miniature.
他变小反而更烦人了
- Do we have a deal, Jack?  - Angelica, I know you.
- 成交吗 Jack?  - Angelica 我了解你
You are not going to steal the life of some innocent man.
你不会去偷取无辜人的寿命
What about the one-legged man?
偷独腿男人的寿命如何?
I need years, Jack.
我需要寿命 Jack
Not for me. For my father.
不是为我自己 是为我爸爸
I am truly the daughter of Blackbeard.
我真的是黑胡子的女儿
You've fallen for your own con, love.
你陷入自己的谎言中了 亲爱的
No, he is my father.
不 他的确是我爸爸
The lies I told you were not lies.
我和你说的谎言 并不是谎言
You lied to me by telling me the truth?
你拿事实来对我说谎?
- Yes.  - That's very good.
- 是  - 这招真不错
- May I use that?  - I'm sure you will, anyway.
- 我可以借用吗?  - 不管怎样 我肯定你都会用这招
Of course I will.
我当然要用
So, will you not give up this quest?
那么 你执意不放弃这次寻找了吗?
I want a father, Jack. I haven't had one.
我想要一位爸爸 Jack 我不曾有过
Angelica, your father, Blackbeard...
Angelica 你的爸爸黑胡子...
he is evil,
他是坏人
and he will kill you given the chance.
情况危急的时候 他甚至会杀你
- He cannot be saved.  - And who are you to set
- 他是无法被救赎的  - 你凭什么
the limits on redemption?
设定救赎一个人的底限?
You stole years of my life, Jack. You owe me.
你偷走了我的生命 Jack 是你亏欠我的
And you are en route to getting yourself killed,
而你这是在自寻死路
and I am not inclined to stand by and watch.
我不能坐视不管
Whitecap Bay!
白帽湾到了!
All hands on deck! Set to the longboats!
全体船员到甲板集合! 上小艇!
Lay 'em out flat!
把网拉平!
No tangles. Make 'em look pretty for our dainty guests.
别让它打结 把它们弄好看一点 准备迎接我们美丽的客人
We're gonna need light. A lot of light.
我们需要光 需要强光
Come!
跟我来!
Smell that? Whale oil. Stuff burns like a miracle from God.
闻到了吗? 是鲸油 烧起来火势就跟上帝创造的奇迹一样
- Can you make it work?  - Made by the English.
- 你能让它正常运作吗?  - 这是英国人制造的
Let's not get our hopes up.
还是别抱太高期望了
The old moon in the arms of the new one.
夏季里初次出现
First of the summer.
新月环抱旧月
Perfect for hunting a mermaid's tear.
非常适合猎取美人鱼的眼泪
We're doomed. They be drawn to man-made light.
我们完了 它们会循着人工的光亮而来
- Sharks?  - Worse than sharks, boy.
- 鲨鱼吗?  - 比鲨鱼还糟糕 孩子
There'll be mermaids upon us within the hour,
记住我的话 在一个小时之内
you mark my words. And we're the bait.
就会有美人鱼接近我们 而我们就是鱼饵
I heard it said a kiss from a mermaid protects a sailor from drowning.
我听说只要得到美人鱼的一个吻 水手便能水淹不死
Don't be a fool! Mermaids are all female, son,
别傻了! 美人鱼都是母的 孩子
and lovely as a dream of heaven.
而且美得无以伦比
But when it comes time to churn butter, so to speak,
但是打个比方 到了拌黄油的时间
they snatch a sailor out of a boat
它们自有办法把水手从小艇
or off the deck of a ship, have their way,
或是大船的甲板上抓走
and then the sailors are pulled to bottom and drowned and eaten.
然后就把他们拖到水底 淹死他们 分而食之
Or, sometimes, the other way around.
有时候 会是截然不同的结局
- Sing.  - What?
- 唱歌  - 什么?
They like to hear singing.
它们喜欢听人唱歌
# My name is Maria #
# 我的名字叫玛利亚 #
# A merchant's daughter fair #
# 我是商人美丽的女儿 #
Louder.
大声点
# And I have left my parents #
# 我离开了自己的父母 #
# And 3,000 pounds a year #
# 以及每年三千英镑的零花钱 #
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特之箭洞穿了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 我唾弃所有闪闪发光的黄金 #
# There is nothing can console me #
# 要问有什么能够慰藉我 #
# But my jolly sailor bold #
# 唯有我可爱的水手那勇敢的心 #
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特之箭洞穿了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 我唾弃所有闪闪发光的黄金 #
# There is nothing can console me #
# 要问有什么能够慰藉我 #
# But my jolly sailor bold #
# 唯有我可爱的水手那勇敢的心 #
Lord save me.
我的天呐
Man, look. Look there.
伙计 看 看那儿
You'll scare her off!
你会把她吓走的!
Aye, and good riddance!
是 走了才好!
Can you talk?
你会说话吗?
Yes.
会
You're beautiful.
你真美
- Are you the one who sings?  - Aye.
- 你就是那个唱歌的人?  - 是
Are you my jolly sailor bold?
你是我可爱勇敢的水手吗?
- Aye, that I be.  - Scrum, comport yourself!
- 是 我就是  - Scrum 冷静点!
Boys! There ain't much been given to me
伙计们! 在我短暂可悲的生命里
in my brief, miserable life, there's the truth in it.
我没得到多少东西 事实就是如此
But, by God, I'll have it said
但是 上帝啊 我要让我的人生里有这件事
that Scrum had himself a kiss from a proper mermaid!
那就是Scrum和一个温柔的美人鱼接吻了!
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特之箭洞穿了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 我唾弃所有闪闪发光的黄金 #
# There is nothing can console me #
# 要问有什么能够慰藉我 #
# But my jolly sailor bold #
# 唯有我可爱的水手那勇敢的心 #
# Come, all you pretty fair maids #
# 美丽的少女们快过来 #
# Whoever you may be #
# 无论你是谁 #
# Who love a jolly sailor bold #
# 只要你爱那些在怒吼的海中 #
# That ploughs the raging sea #
# 开辟天地的可爱勇敢的水手 #
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特之箭洞穿了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 我唾弃所有闪闪发光的黄金 #
# There is nothing can console me #
# 要问有什么能够慰藉我 #
# But my jolly sailor bold #
# 唯有我可爱的水手那勇敢的心 #
# My heart is pierced by Cupid #
# 丘比特之箭洞穿了我的心 #
# I disdain all glittering gold #
# 我唾弃所有闪闪发光的黄金 #
# There is nothing can console me #
# 要问有什么能够慰藉我 #
# But my jolly sailor bold #
# 唯有我可爱的水手那勇敢的心 #
Out upon it! It has begun!
看小艇那边! 美人鱼开始进攻了!
Light 'em up!
把它们点着!
Muster your courage! Drive 'em to shore!
鼓起你们的勇气! 把她们往海滩赶!
Nets into the water! Quickly!
把网拉到水里! 快点!
Retreat, all, to land! For your lives!
撤退 所有人上岸! 保命要紧!
Retreat, I say!
我说了 快撤退!
Cowards! Back in the water!
胆小鬼! 回到水里去!
There be no refuge on land! On my word!
回到陆地上也不会活命! 我向你们保证!
Come on!
快点!